<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>🐇🕳️ on Escape Velocity</title>
    <link>http://cunger.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 🐇🕳️ on Escape Velocity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cunger.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Network programming</title>
      <link>http://cunger.github.io/blog/network-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cunger.github.io/blog/network-programming/</guid>
      <description>Computer networking 101 The point of a network is to send data between machines.
The nodes of the network are physical devices like computers or printers. The connection between them can be wired, for example Ethernet cables, or wireless, like WiFi.
Each physical node has a network interface card, a piece of hardware that can translate between digital data and the signals sent over the network.
Since the operating system controls access to hardware, it controls the network interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diskrete Kosinustransformation</title>
      <link>http://cunger.github.io/blog/dct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cunger.github.io/blog/dct/</guid>
      <description>Digitale Bilder und Bildkompression In der Digitalfotographie werden Bilder als Bitmaps aufgenommen und dargestellt: als  \(M\times N\)  -Raster von quadratischen Bildelementen (Pixeln), wobei  \(M\)  die Breite und  \(N\)  die Höhe des Bildes in Pixeln ist.
Jeder einzelne Pixel kann  \(2^b\)  Werte annehmen, üblicherweise von  \(0\)  bis  \(2^b-1\)  für ein geeignetes  \(b\in\mathbb{N}\)  . Dabei wird  \(b\)  als Bittiefe bezeichnet und entspricht der Anzahl von Bits, die für die Speicherung der Information eines Pixels benötigt werden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change reloaded</title>
      <link>http://cunger.github.io/blog/climate-change-reloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cunger.github.io/blog/climate-change-reloaded/</guid>
      <description>When I first learned about climate change, there was plenty of uncertainty and time. It was one of many problems. And it was easy to ignore.
Now the game has changed.
Here are my main takeaways from studying the current climate landscape at Terra.do. Don&amp;rsquo;t take them as hard facts, but as an invitation to reconsider and update what you understand and think about climate change.
It&amp;rsquo;s serious. Climate change is happening.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
