<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Escape Velocity</title>
    <link>http://cunger.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Escape Velocity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cunger.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Favorite books 2021</title>
      <link>http://cunger.github.io/blog/books-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cunger.github.io/blog/books-2021/</guid>
      <description>Ryusho Kadota, Akira Tokuhiro, Simon Varnam: On the brink: The inside story of Fukushima Daiichi.
Merlin Sheldrake: Entangled life: How fungi make our worlds, change our minds &amp;amp; shape our futures.
Becky Chambers: Long way to a small angry planet.
Kim Stanley Robinson: The ministry for the future.
Brian Cox: The planets.
Scott Kelly: Endurance: A year in space, a lifetime of discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are all terraformers</title>
      <link>http://cunger.github.io/blog/we-are-all-terraformers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cunger.github.io/blog/we-are-all-terraformers/</guid>
      <description>Today is Drawdown Day and it starts with a cool morning breeze, the first one since last week&amp;rsquo;s heat wave.
The radio announces that it&amp;rsquo;s 7 am as I pass by the basalt statues on my way to work. Although I must have seen them a hundred times, I still marvel at them. Ten tons of sequestered carbon, formed into a row of extinct animals, marching as if they were leaving Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing up for nuclear</title>
      <link>http://cunger.github.io/blog/standup-for-nuclear-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cunger.github.io/blog/standup-for-nuclear-2021/</guid>
      <description>It’s a scenic location, right in front of the Brandenburger Tor. Polar bears rollerskate and dance across the square. Someone is juggling, while songs about nuclear energy sound from the loudspeakers. Pro-nuclear advocates might not make a crowd, but they surely know how to have fun.
The demonstration is well timed. People who have been at COP26 in Glasgow don’t mind a stop in Berlin on their way home, including James Hansen himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change reloaded</title>
      <link>http://cunger.github.io/blog/climate-change-reloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cunger.github.io/blog/climate-change-reloaded/</guid>
      <description>When I first learned about climate change, there was plenty of uncertainty and time. It was one of many problems. And it was easy to ignore.
Now the game has changed.
Here are my main takeaways from studying the current climate landscape at Terra.do. Don&amp;rsquo;t take them as hard facts, but as an invitation to reconsider and update what you understand and think about climate change.
It&amp;rsquo;s serious. Climate change is happening.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
